Adams family papers
Litchfield Historical Society
- Correspondence
  - Deming, Frances Adams (1847-1901)
    - Deming, Frances Adams to Adams, Sarah, circa 1860 Jun (Folder 1)
      Frances writes to her sister and hopes she will be very much better when she returns. Mary attended a wedding and a party at the Pinnacle. Frances mentions Julia, Susie Rogers, and Sophie. Frances likes school and would go all summer if father wanted her to.
  - De Puy, Harriet Adams (1822-1914)
    Harriet Adams De Puy was the daughter of Amos and Eliza Dean Adams.
    - De Puy, Harriet Adams, 1845, 1879 (Folder 1)
      - De Puy, Harriet Adams to Adams, Joseph and Adams, Deborah Marsh, 1845 May 3 (Folder 1)
        De Puy writes from Bath about the death of sister Ann Eliza. The health of her family is good and she enjoys their company. She hears that Joseph and Deborah Adams may visit Bath in the summer and nothing would please her more than seeing them.
      - De Puy, Harriet Adams to Adams, Charles, 1879 Sep 30 (Folder 1)
        De Puy writes from New York City about her family history.
  - Doty, T.
    - Doty, T. to Terry, James, 1870 May 17 (Folder 1)
      Telegram sent from Champaign, Ill., which informs Terry that J. H. Adams died there. Will put body in vault and wait fro instruction.
  - Graves, Mary Hinman (1812-1856)
    Mary Hinman Graves (1812-1856) was the sister of Julia Hinman Adams, wife of Charles Adams.
    - Graves, Mary Hinman, 1850-1853 (Folder 1)
      Five letters to her sister and father.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil, 1850 Aug 9 (Folder 1)
        Graves writes from Bristol, R.I. Her husband has become so debilitated by the heat that they have left Jamaica and moved to the home of father Graves. If Mr. Graves's health improves, they will return before the cold weather. Her husband endured the voyage from Kingston but is weak.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1850 Oct 2 (Folder 1)
        Graves writes from Bristol, R.I. Mr. Graves is in very weak condition. It is not possible that he can live long in his present emaciated, feeble state. Julia Adams forwarded this letter to Scovil Hinman with an additional note to say that she is now safely in Litchfield after a recently traveling 800 miles to visit family.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil, 1851 Feb 27 (Folder 1)
        Graves writes from Bristol, R.I., that she has returned from Boston and is staying with father Graves. She is lonely and imagines how lonely her father is, and wishes she had a home into which she could take him and care for him, but her future plans are uncertain.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman to Hinman, Scovil, 1852 Feb (Folder 1)
        Graves writes from Hartford. She is visiting, but she is actively engaged with her needle and her pen to assist in the support of her dear son and herself. She describes activities in Hartford and her's son religious inclinations.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman to Adams, Julia Himan, 1853 Feb 8 (Folder 1)
        Graves writes from Framingham, Mass. She has been in East Boston, where Charlie is attending school. She describes her activities in Boston. She wishes she could attend to her father, but is duty bound to provide for Charlie. The letter has a note from Mary Adams indicating it was sent on to Scovil Hinman.
      - Graves, Mary Hinman, empty envelope addressed to Hinman, Scovil, [circa 1850s] Mar 26 (Folder 1)
  - Hinman, Mary Coles
    Mary Coles Hinman was the second wife of Scovil Hinman, father-in-law of Charles Adams.
    - Hinman, Mary Coles, 1858-circa 1864 (Folder 1)
      Four letters to her step-grandchildren.
      - Hinman, Mary Coles to unnamed stepchildren, 1858 Oct 18 (Folder 1)
        Hinman writes from New Haven with news of her and her husband's activities and her desire to see the children.
      - Hinman, Mary Coles to Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1861 Oct 7 (Folder 1)
        Hinman writes from Stonington, Conn., about her activties there, family and friends, and her desire to see her grandchildren.
      - Hinman, Mary Coles to Adams, Sarah, 1861 Oct 8 (Folder 1)
        Hinman writes from Stonington, Conn., about her family and friends and her activities.
      - Hinman, Mary Coles to unnamed stepchildren, circa 1864 May 24 (Folder 1)
        Hinman writes from New Haven about her wish to visit Litchfield, her attire and that of her grandchildren, what she has been eating, and other activities.
  - Hubbard, John H. (John Henry) (1804-1872)
    - Hubbard, John H., 1864 (Folder 1)
      Correspondence related to the death of Charles Adams (1845-1864) from wounds received during the Civil War Battle of Cold Harbor.
      - Hubbard, John H., 1864 Jun 11 (Folder 1)
        Unaddressed telegraph message stating that Charlie Adams died this morning. "I was with him." Offers a few additional details.
      - Hubbard, John H. to his wife, 1864 Jun 11 (Folder 1)
        Writing from Washington, D.C., Hubbard describes the circumstances surrounding the death of Charles Adams (1845-1864) and the arrangements he is making for transfer of the body to Litchfield.
      - Hubbard, John H., ledger sheet, 1864 Jun 11 (Folder 1)
        Contains copies of his correspondence related to the death of Charles Adams.
  - May, Betsey Adams (1796-1877)
    Betsey Adams May was a daughter of Joseph Adams.
    - Buel, C. [Charlotte?] to May, Betsey Adams, 1815 Aug 28 (Folder 1)
      Buel writes from Troy, N.Y., with news of her and her family's health. Her mother begs Betsey's mother to accept the shawl for Betsey and the vest for Amos.
    - May, Betsey Adams, 1868-1869 (Folder 2)
      Two letters written from Bath, N.Y. to her brother.
      - May, Betsey Adams to Adams, Charles, 1868 Jan 31 (Folder 2)
        May writes about comfort of Julia and Adams now small family, but that he is not far away from them should he need to visit. She reports on her family's health and activities. There have been many changes in Bath since he was there. She never receives letters from the Adams family.
      - May, Betsey Adams to Adams, Charles, 1869 Jan 8 (Folder 2)
        May writes that because of her eyes, it is hard for her to write or read. She reports on her and her family's health and activities and is sorry to hear Julia is doing so poorly. She hopes they can visit this summer and recalls their visit last summer. Bath has been visited by another fire this winter.
  - Richards, Amos Adams (1794-1872)
    Amos Adams Richards (1794-1872) was the son of Giles and Sally (Adams) Richards. Joseph Adams was his uncle.
    - Richards, Amos Adams, 1813, 1866 (Folder 1)
      Two letters, one to his uncle and one to his cousin.
      - Richards, Amos Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1813 Aug 1 (Folder 1)
        Richards writes from Boston about his and his family's health, his father's plan to give up his tools so he and Giles can establish themselves in Smithfield, R.I., how they plan to establish a business, American and British ships, and finding a place for Amos, but there has never been a worse time for business
      - Richards, Amos Adams to Adams, Charles, 1866 Dec 14 (Folder 1)
        Richards writes from Urbana, Ohio, and recalls visiting Litchfield in 1813 and other events in his life, reports on his family, recalls what he knows of Adams's family, and discusses his philosophy of life.
  - Richards, Sarah Adams (1769-1836)
    Sarah Adams Richards was a sister of Joseph Adams.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1798 Jun 12 (Folder 1)
      Richards writes from Charleston, S.C. about their late brother Thomas's affairs, a new baby has been added to the family, Mr. Richards traveling in New Hampshire and is much perplexed about his business matters, and family news.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams, 1800 (Folder 2)
      Two letters written in Cambridge, Mass., to her brother.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1800 Oct 1 (Folder 2)
        Richards writes that she has not heard from him in over twelve months. She would like to visit, but Mr. Giles business requires him to travel and if he heads for the vicinity of Litchfield, she will accompany him. She reports on her and her family's health.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1800 Nov 23 (Folder 2)
        Richards writes about her pleasure of hearing from Adams. Mr. Richards has been out of health lately provoked by his business affairs, but he has lately improved them to avoid embarrassment. He is at a loss as to what business to persue. She regrets being at a distance from her only brother. She reports on family health. She would be eager to read any news from the widow of their brother.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams, 1811-1813 (Folder 3)
      Three letters to her brother Joseph Adams.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1811 Jun 29 (Folder 3)
        Richards reports on family news and health and the possibility of visiting Adams.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1813 Apr 11 (Folder 3)
        Richards writes from Boston to report he death of their nephew William in Camden, S.C. and the status of his personal property and real estate and claims made against it. She would like Adams to render his opinion on the matter. She reports on the health of the family.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1813 Jul 11 (Folder 3)
        Richards writes from Boston thanking Adams for his kind attention to Amos. She offers her opinion concerning the Camden property and reports on health of family members.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams, 1816-1819 (Folder 4)
      Three letters written in Dedham, Mass., to her brother Joseph Adams.
      - Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1816 Feb 1 (Folder 4)
        Richards writes that she has not heard from Adams in two years. She reports on her family and Mr. Richards's business affairs. They have purchased a house and property in Dedham and have no family there "but George and Mary and a colour'd girl of which I have had two years which I am to keep till she is 18." She encourages Adams to move to Dedham.
      - Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1818 Jun 21 (Folder 4)
        Richards writes about the health and news of her family and friends. They have made improvements to her house. Mr. Richards is better and is resuming his business.
      - Adams, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1819 Aug (Folder 4)
        Richards writes about loss of her dear Sarah. Mr. Lawrence has broken up his house and sent his children to relatives. She reports additional family news. She feels older and more broken down than their sister and is not up to writing.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1827 Nov 26 (Folder 5)
      Richards writes from Dedham, Mass., commenting on Adams's letter in which he reports on his family. She reports on the health and news of her family. She is glad Adams is attached to a minister and describes the many churches and liberal preaching in her neighborhood.
    - Richards, Sarah Adams, 1829-1834 (Folder 6)
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1829 Mar 22 (Folder 6)
        Richards writes from Dedham, Mass., about the health of her family. She intended to ask Kezia to spend the winter, but Mr. Richards's health did not permit it. She relates news of her family.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1831 Sep 25 (Folder 6)
        She writes from Dayton, Ohio, about her health. She believes it best to stay close to her children, describes their business activities and activities of other family members and friends. She discusses philosophical differences in churches.
      - Richards, Sarah Adams to Adams, Joseph, 1834 Jan 7 (Folder 6)
        Richards writes from Boston. She has been to Vermont where she hoped her health would improve. She relates news of family and friends.
    - Lawrence, Amos (1786-1852) to Richards, Sarah Adams, 1833 Jun 27 (Folder 7)
      Lawrence writes to his former mother-in-law from Boston. His son William will meet her in Litchfield to accompany her to Boston. He reports news of family health and activities. He does not attend to business much, but provides counsel to his partners. He discusses arrangements for her stay.
  - Rogers, Kezia Adams (1811-1899)
    Kezia Adams Rogers was the daughter of Joseph and Deborah Marsh Adams.
    - Rogers, Kezia Adams, 1869-1870 (Folder 1)
      Three letters to her brother Charles Adams.
      - Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles, 1869 May 30 (Folder 1)
        Rogers writes from Dresden, Germany, about James How's death. She express her sympathy for Julia and discusses her situation. They are enjoying Dresden very much and she describes it, the people, and their religion.
      - Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles, 1869 Oct 14 (Folder 1)
        Rogers writes from Buffalo that she was shocked to learn that Julia had died and expresses her sympathies. She discusses her husband's illness. She writes about visitors and the difficulty in taking up housekeeping after traveling.
      - Rogers, Kezia Adams to Adams, Charles, 1870 Dec 11 (Folder 1)
        Rogers writes from Buffalo about her relocation and the long, tedious process of packing the books and storing the belongings. She is not going to worry any more about the future. She enjoyed his and the girls' visit. She reports news of family and reflects on her long life.
  - Wessells, Julia Adams How (1842-?)
    Julia Adams How Wessells (1842-?) was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.
    - Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1859 (Folder 1)
      Four letters written from Buffalo to family members.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1859 Jan 30 (Folder 1)
        Wessells writes about teaching her scholars. She is surprised to read in The Litchfield Enquirer her marriage notice and relates news of family and friends.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Baldwin, Ella Adams, circa 1859 (Folder 1)
        Letter to her little sister.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1859 Feb 6 (Folder 1)
        Wessells writes responding to her mother's recent letter which described lively winter activities in Litchfield. She writes about skating, her studies, news of friends and family, and attending entertainments.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1859 Apr 17 (Folder 1)
        Wessells writes about her activities, including attending a magic lantern exhibition and a concert, her enjoyment of music, the condition of Adams's eyes, and news of family and friends.
    - Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1860 (Folder 2)
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1860 Feb 19 (Folder 2)
        Wessells writes from Buffalo about news of family and friends, school, and social activities.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Peck, Sarah Adams, 1860 Jul 24 (Folder 2)
        Wessells writes to her aunt about family news and her social activities.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1860 Aug 16 (Folder 2)
        Wessells writes to her mother about her arrival back in Litchfield, people who have called on her or she has called on, and a joke in a telegram.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1860 Sep 20 (Folder 2)
        Wessells writes to her mother from Buffalo about new of family and friends, her schooling, and social calls she and others have made.
    - Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1861-1862 (Folder 3)
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1861 Mar 17 (Folder 3)
        Wessells writes from Buffalo to her sister about surprise at receiving a letter from her given her condition, news of family and friends, entertainments she has attended, her schooling, and the national political climate and President Lincoln.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1861 Apr 11 (Folder 3)
        Wessell writes to her sister from Buffalo about Adams's illness, news of family and friends, the news from the South and civil war, singing a song at a school concert, and attending musical events.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Sarah, 1862 Mar 2 (Folder 3)
        Wessells writes from Buffalo to her sister to wish her a happy birthday, news of family and friends, making a catalogue of uncle's library, her singing, and social activities.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1862 May 18 (Folder 3)
        Wessells writes to her mother that they are getting along well with sewing and housekeeping, this is father's fifty-seventh birthday, they have visited Sarah's grave, she supposes her mother will be in Buffalo soon and recommends friends to visit.
    - Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1863-1865 (Folder 4)
      Six letters to family members.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles and Adams, Julia Hinman, 1863 Mar 29 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes about her mother's health, her constant thoughts about Frankie and Sarah, and Mary's health.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles, 1863 Jun 12 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about travels of family members, their residence, her daily routine, news of family and friends, her happy marriage and good husband, and Jim obtaining a piano.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1863 Jul 22 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about getting Adams a dress, her health, recent visitors, news of family and friends, being alone and what she is reading.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1864 Mar 28 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about her and her husband's health, the New York Fair and Sanitary Commission, dining at Willow St., and news of family and friends.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles, 1864 May 18 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about Adams's fifty-ninth birthday, well wishes from friends, recent visitors, and socializing.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles, 1865 May 18 (Folder 4)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about her fathers's sixtieth birthday, her loneliness without her husband, and family news.
    - Wessells, Julia Adams How, 1866-1869 (Folder 5)
      Five letters to family members.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1866 Jan 28 (Folder 5)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn to her sister about her sister's birthday, health of family members, upcoming visit to Litchfield, longing for a sleigh ride, news of friends, and social activities.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1866 Sep 16 (Folder 5)
        Wessells writes from West Hampton, N.Y., about their sudden trip there. She describes her impressions of the landscape and relates family news.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1868 May 23 (Folder 5)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn about Mary's miscarriage last night.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1869 May 2 (Folder 5)
        Wessells writes from Brooklyn that she has no heart for writing, but feels that she ought to. She longs to see her mother, and her friends are very kind. She thanks God for her two children and prays for strength to take care of them.
      - Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Henry, 1869 Oct 26 (Folder 5)
        Wessells writes from Terryville, Conn., to her brother about coming up from New Haven with Jimmy and grandmother. She will be glad to be home again. She hopes father is improving and Fannie keeps well.
  - Wheelock, Mary Adams (1838-1895)
    Mary Adams Wheelock (1838-1895) was the daughter of Charles and Julia Hinman Adams.
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1855-1860 (Folder 1)
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1855 Oct 27 (Folder 1)
        Wheelock writes to her father about school and news of family and friends.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1858 Sep 10 (Folder 1)
        Wheelock writes about family health, her mother's travels, the presents recently received, visitors, and news of family and friends.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles, 1860 Jun 29 (Folder 1)
        Wheelock writes that they have arrived in Washington from Buffalo. Uncle escorted them about the city. They will leave for Litchfield on the early train on Monday. They called on the Hows yesterday and go to Greenwood today and Central Park tomorrow.
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1862 (Folder 2)
      Two letters to her mother.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1862 May 21 (Folder 2)
        Wheelock writes that she is glad her mother has arrived in Bath, N.Y. She writes about activities in their home, health and news of family and friends, wishing her a good visit, and Julia and her giving their father "The Memorial Vol. of the American Board of Missions" for his birthday.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams and Adams, Charles to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1862 May 25 (Folder 2)
        Wheelock writes that she is glad her mother is having a pleasant visit. She has reassigned bedrooms for the children and reports on activities in their home. She reports news of friends and family. Her mother must not think of returning for weeks because they are getting along splendidly. They have received many kind letters of sympathy. She received a letter from Charley; he was in the Battle of Williamsburg and says he cannot see how he escaped being killed or wounded. Charles Adams writes that they are getting along nicely and all are well.
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1863 (Folder 3)
      Five letters to her parents.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams and Wessells, Julia Adams How to Adams, Charles, 1863 Mar 18 (Folder 3)
        Wheelock writes to thank her father for the his letter and the money. She is delighted mother has been to Dea. Catlins and had the neighbors in for tea. Wessells writes that she is delighted to hear about mother's health. They have received a call from Brigadier General Carlin, who has been in a great deal of hard fighting. She went to the art gallery and describes social activities. She received a beautiful philopoena from Mr. Worthington.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1863 Mar 23 (Folder 3)
        Wheelock writes that she and Auntie went to Bath, N.Y. and reports on family there. She was glad to receive letters from her mother and father. She has thought much of Sarah and Frankie and is very sad. She reports on family news and asks wonders about family and why father resigned as deputy sheriff.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1863 May 4 (Folder 3)
        Wheelock is glad is mother is gaining strength. She is pleased that the 19th regiment did not join Hooker. She discusses dresses for her sisters, the upcoming visit, and other matters related to Julia's wedding.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1863 Dec 16 (Folder 3)
        Wheelock writes that she has not been out, but had a number of callers. Yesterday, she attended a historical lecture. She describes other social activities.
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to [?], circa 1863 (Folder 3)
        Letter fragment. Wheelock discusses brides' maids dresses, a possible trip to Jamestown, and an invitation to visit from Clara Beebe Darling.
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1864-65 (Folder 4)
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Julia Hinman, 1864 Nov 30 (Folder 4)
        Wheelock writes from home of family and domestic news.
      - [United States. Dept of Agriculture] to Wheelock, Mary Adams, circa 1864 (Folder 4)
      - Wheelock, Mary Adams to Adams, Charles and Adams, Julia Hinman, 1865 Aug 4 (Folder 4)
        Wheelock writes from Buffalo about her journey there and whom she traveled with. She met a man who knew Charles fifteen years ago. She is very glad she made the journey by herself this time and had no trouble. She reports news of family and friends.
    - Wheelock, Mary Adams, 1870-1872 (Folder 5)
      Six letters written in Brooklyn, N.Y. to her father.